We made it back alive.
生きて戻ってきた
But,
けど…
can the Agency look past the
thirty-five people she murdered?
彼女の３５人殺しを探偵社は許すだろうか
What am I going to do if the
Agency doesn't accept her?
もし彼女と探偵社が対立したら　僕はどうすれば
Good morning.
お早う御座います
Can you turn around for me?
ちょっとぐるっと回ってみて～
So cute!
可～愛い
What's going on?
何やってるんですか
Well, she looks good in anything.
だって彼女　何着てもすっごく似合うんだもの
No, that's not what I'm talking about.
いや　そこではなくて
Kunikida-san...
国木田さん
Don't look at me like that.
そんな目で見るな　俺も止めたのだ
I tried to stop them, too.
I wonder if this is going to work out.
大丈夫なのかな
Maybe it's not such a good idea.
矢っ張りまずいかな
Even if everyone else is okay with it,
皆さんがよくても　乱歩さんなんかこの手の規則は気にするんじゃ
Rampo-san might be a
stickler about the rules.
Oh, don't worry about that.
それは大丈夫
I'm back!
ただいま
I bought some!
買ってきたよ～
乱歩さんが一番浮かれてるから
Rampo-san's into it the most.
This is the snack I told you about earlier.
これ　先刻話したねると色が変わるお菓子
It changes color when you mix it.
Go ahead, mix it.
ねっていいよ
First, open the bag,
先ずは袋を開けて容器に二種類の粉を入れて水を少々加えます
then put the two powders in the container,
They're like siblings
in elementary school.
and add some water.
小学生の…兄妹？
続いてよく混ぜりましょう
Next, mix really well.
ここで愛情をかけてねるねるするのが大事
It's important to put your feelings into it.
は～い　ねるねるねるねるねるねる
Okay? Mix, mix, mix, mix, mix, mix, mix.
よくかき混ぜたら　あら不思議
And look, how strange!
But I'm the one who gets to eat it.
でも食べるのはぼ～く
How childish.
大人げない
Rampo-san, you're a terrible person!
乱歩さん非道いですね
Well, it's just like him to do that.
ま　乱歩さんらしいですけど
それが大人のすることなんですか　ったくもう
So, who called her over to the Agency?
でも　彼女を探偵社に呼んだのは誰なんです？
私だ
It was me.
President!
社長
Any movement from the police?
警察の動向は
Thanks to the Port Mafia's
attempts to erase her identity,
ポートマフィアの隠蔽の甲斐あってか　身元までは割れていませんが
they haven't tracked down who she is yet.
But she'll be a wanted fugitive soon.
指名手配は時間の問題か
Please let me stay here.
ここに置いてください
What?
I'll do anything.
何でもします
I don't recommend it.
やめておけ
It's not because you were
with the Port Mafia,
元マフィアだからではない　仕事がないわけでもない
or because we don't have work.
But don't do it.
だがやめておけ
It's not easy, the world we live in.
甘い世界ではないぞ
Besides, if you stay here,
それにここにいたら　いずれマフィアに見つかる
the Mafia will find you eventually.
むしろ遠くに逃げたほうが
Shouldn't you run somewhere far away?
He said
私には　殺しの外には何もできないとあいつは云った
that I could do nothing
else but kill people.
I want to prove to myself that he's wrong.
違うと自分に証明したい
President.
社長
I would also like to ask on her behalf.
僕からもお願いします
Please.
お願いです
Please...
お願い…です
Very well.
よかろう
え！？
What?!
I'll take her in.
私が預かる
そ
の
重
い
足
を
膝
前
へ
導
く
sono omoi ashi o hiza o mae ni michibiku
That feeling pulls your feet onward,
その重い足を膝を前へ導く
负
责
人
Maki
负责人
chikara nanda tte Go ahead to
Telling you to go ahead towards a new power.
力
は
何
だ
っ
て
Go
ahead
問
う
力は何だって Go ahead 問う
君
の
中
に
生
じ
る
衝
動
は
treasure
kimi no naka ni shoujiru shoudou wa Treasure
That impulse born within you is a treasure!
君の中に生じる衝動はtreasure
honmon ka nisemono ka tsureteike yo
Whether it's real or fake, just take it along!
日
听
小
伍
长
田
Cris
翻
译
兰
樱
Naga
校
对
小
伍
江
本
物
か
偽
物
か
つ
れ
て
行
け
よ
日听
小伍
长田Cris
翻译
兰樱
Naga
校对
小伍
小江
本物か偽物か つれて行けよ
kuusou no kanata notte boku no mata mo taemai yo
Straddling the limits of this fantasy, my legs probably won't last,
空
想
の
彼
方
ま
で
僕
の
中
怠
慢
よ
空想の彼方まで 僕の中の怠慢よ
soredemo ii yo yume demo
But that's just fine, even if it's only a dream.
时
间
轴
阿
水
压
制
Coolkid
さ
ら
っ
て
も
い
よ
夢
で
も
时间轴
阿水
压制
Coolkid
さらってもいいよ 夢でも
todokisou de todokanai Make some noise
It seems within reach, but somehow too far off, so make some noise!
届
き
そ
う
で
届
か
な
い
make
some
noise
届きそうで届かない make some noise
Are these empty days gonna start shining bright?
kuukyo na nichijou wa kagayakidasu noka
空
虚
な
日
常
は
輝
き
出
す
の
か
空虚な日常は輝き出すのか
吐
き
出
す
よ
う
に
し
て
前
に
漕
げ
ば
hakidasu you ni shite mae ni mae ni kogeba
If we push on through like we're about to hurl,
吐き出すようにして前に前に漕げば
bokura no mirai wa kasoku shiteyuku darou
I'm sure our future will start to pick up speed!
僕
ら
の
未
来
は
加
速
し
て
い
く
だ
ろ
う
僕らの未来は加速していくだろう
今
こ
の
時
が
止
ま
る
と
し
て
も
ima kono toki ga tomaru to shitemo kono kokyuu made
Even if this moment in time becomes frozen,
今この時が止まるとしても
こ
の
呼
吸
ま
で
止
め
ら
れ
は
し
な
い
さ
この呼吸まで止められはしないさ
tomerare wa shinai sa kudaranai gohoubi mada?
There's no stopping this breath, so where's my worthless reward?
く
だ
ら
な
い
くだらない
ご
褒
美
ま
だ
？
ご褒美まだ？
本字幕由诸神字幕组出品，仅供学习交流，禁止用于商业用途
更多中日双语字幕，尽在 www.kamigami.org 和微博 @诸神字幕组
Slight fracture of the lower jaw,
下顎骨剥離骨折　前頭骨・胸椎裂離
诸神微信公众号正式上线啦，搜索「诸神字幕组」添加关注吧
avulsion of the pedicles
and the T2 thoracic vertebrae,
damage to the jugular ligament,
頸部靱帯損傷　上腕・大腿筋断裂
rupture of the brachial
and femoral muscles,
and first-degree burns over the entire body.
全身Ⅰ度熱傷　そして昏睡
To top it off, he's in a coma.
He's suffered serious damage.
派手に毀損されたものだね
It is the price he paid
for failing his mission.
任務失敗の代償というわけだ
I'm sorry.
申し訳ありません
He may not regain consciousness.
このまま意識が戻らないかもしれないね
But...
そんな…
Don't feel so disappointed.
気を落とすことはない
You all did your best.
君達はよく頑張ったよ
You did fail in attacking the Agency and
確かに探偵社の襲撃に失敗し　人虎の捕獲を謬り　輸送船を沈めたけど
capturing the weretiger,
and you sank the transport ship.
But you did your best, didn't you?
頑張ったからいいじゃないか
Effort is what's important.
頑張りが大事　結果は二の次だ　そうだろう
Results come second.
Isn't that right?
Oh, that reminds me.
そうそう
作戦中に芥川君が潰したカルマ・トランジットの残党が手勢を集めているそうだ
The remnants of Karma Transit,
the group Akutagawa-kun crushed
during the operation,
are apparently coming together.
I presume they want
vengeance on Akutagawa-kun.
芥川君への復讐だろう
Listen, Higuchi-kun.
いいかね　樋口君
The Mafia are, in the end,
マフィアの本質は暴力を貨幣とした経済行為体だ
an act of commerce that
employs violence as its currency.
It is allowed to desire and
kill anything and anyone.
何を求めても　誰を殺してもいい
Retaliation in kind is a matter
of expenditure and liability.
だが暴力を返されることは
支出であり　負債だよ
But, liability?
そんな　負債などと
Akutagawa-senpai has accomplished
much in his missions thus far.
芥川先輩はこれまでの任務で多大な成果を
Indeed, Akutagawa-kun is competent.
確かに芥川君は優秀だ
His propensity for violence is high,
even for our organization.
彼の暴力性は組織でも抜きん出ている
But what about you?
では君は？
Higuchi-kun,
樋口君
君は自分がこの仕事に向いてると思ったことはあるかね
have you ever felt that you were
actually suited for this job?
Episode 11 Part 1
An Unsuitable
Profession for Her
I look horrible.
非道い顔
That's quite enough for rehearsals, Gin.
予演はそれぐらいにしておけ　銀
The Black Lizard!
黒蜥蜴か
Gin's often stuck with dark jobs like
infiltration and assassination.
銀の野郎はやれ潜入だ暗殺だっつう陰気な仕事が多くてな
It's not unusual for him to have
to slit the throat of one of our own
上の勅命で身内の喉を掻き切るなんてしょっちゅうだ
by a higher-up's command.
When it's for real, you won't
even have time to be surprised.
本番は驚く暇もないぜ
You're saying the boss will terminate me?
首領が私を始末すると？
Not at the moment.
今はない
But I don't know about tomorrow.
だが　明日はわからぬ
Are you here to mock me?
私を嘲いに来たのですか
If I were in your situation,
私があなたの立場なら　暗殺者が枕元に来る前に身の振り方を考え直す
I'd rethink my current position before
an assassin arrives at my doorstep.
You, along with Akutagawa-kun,
首領直轄の遊撃部隊である芥川君とあなたは我々武闘派組を動かす権限がある
are a strike force under the
boss's direct supervision.
As such, you have the authority to give
orders to us in the combat squad.
In that sense, you are our superior.
いわば上司だ
But what makes us obey is not your authority,
だが我々を傅かせるのは権限ではない
but fear and respect for the
ability Akutagawa-kun wields.
芥川君の持つ力への畏怖と崇敬だ
Higuchi-kun,
樋口君
for the time while
Akutagawa-kun is incapacitated,
芥川君の動けぬ今　あなたに我々が従いたいと思わせる何かがあるか
do you possess anything
that motivates us to obey?
I don't need your help!
お前の扶けなど要らぬ
Akutagawa-senpai!
芥川先輩
Even for you, this would be suicide!
いくら先輩でも自殺行為です
You're walking right into a
building full of security guards!
警備員が詰める屋舎に正面から乗り込むなどと
You didn't even give us subordinates
any orders about how to support you—
然も　我々部下への援護指示もなく
黙れ
Shut up!
What would you know about any of this?
お前に何がわかる
That's a sign.
狼煙だ
A sign visible from anywhere in the city.
この街のどこからでも見える狼煙
It is a powerful sign that
will be seen by the one
僕の力を認めぬまま　触れも断りもなく消えた
who left without a word,
and without acknowledging my power.
彼の人の目に否応なく届く太い狼煙
But it's my job to help you, senpai!
ですが　先輩を扶けるのが私の仕事です
I don't need your help!
お前の扶けなど要らぬ
I don't need anyone's help!
誰の扶けも
I'm back.
ただいま
Have you ever felt that you were
actually suited for this job?
君は自分がこの仕事に向いてると思ったことはあるかね
Of course not, there's no way.
そんなの　あるわけないでしょ
Yes? This is Higuchi.
はい　樋口
What?!
何ですって
I urge you to reconsider.
再思したまえ
Your actions are contrary to
what the brass would want.
上意に悖る
Are you insane?
姐さん　正気か　自殺行為だぜ
That's suicide!
芥川の兄人を掠ったのはカルマ・トランジットの残党が雇った国外の傭兵だ
Akutagawa was abducted by foreign mercs
hired by Karma Transit's remnants!
Not only do they have numbers on their side,
数が揃ってるうえ　重火器でこれでもかってほど武装してやがる
they're armed to the teeth!
The boss will eventually issue orders
to conduct a retrieval operation.
直に首領から奪還作戦の指示が来る
それまで待て
Wait until that happens!
There will be no order!
指示は永遠に来ません
If we retaliate as an
organization against smugglers
芥川個人を襲った密輸屋に対し　組織をあげて反撃すれば
who targeted
Akutagawa-senpai as an individual,
他の組織にも飛び火して大規模抗争になる
the fallout will trigger
conflicts with other organizations.
To avoid that,
それを避ける為　上は構成員個人の諍いとして捨て置く心算です
the brass will turn a blind eye to a
personal dispute between individual members.
Akutagawa-senpai has been cut off.
芥川先輩は切り捨てられた
But what can you hope
to do by yourself?
だが　あんた一人如きで何ができるんだ
Nothing.
何もできませんよ
Still!
でも　何もしないなんて
I can't stand by and do nothing!
私には無理です
I knew...
わかっていた
I knew I wasn't suited for this job.
私がこの仕事に向いていないことも
I knew I didn't have my
subordinates' respect.
部下が私に敬意を払っていないことも
If I were in your situation,
私があなたの立場なら　暗殺者が枕元に来る前に身の振り方を考え直す
I'd rethink my current position before
an assassin arrives at my doorstep.
It's not easy to leave the Port Mafia,
ポートマフィアを抜けるのは容易ではないが　不可能ではない
but it's not impossible.
I've thought about it many times.
何度も考えたことだ
Yet I didn't, because...
それでも私がそうしなかったのは…
Crap.
しまった
I can't rescue
Akutagawa-senpai with this injury.
この傷では先輩を…
Yet I didn't, because...
それでも私が　そうしなかったのは…
Kill everyone you don't recognize!
知らねぇ顔は全員殺せ
Why is the Black Lizard here?
黒蜥蜴がどうして…
You are our superior officer.
あなたは我々の上司だ
If our superior officer is in danger,
上司の危機とあっては　動かぬわけにもいくまい
we must act.
I guess we're about done here.
ざっとこんなもんか
Akutagawa-senpai...
芥川…先輩…
Senpai...
先輩　先輩
Senpai!
Higuchi?
樋口…か
Senpai, you're bleeding.
先輩
血が…
I'm sorry.
済まんな
It's not easy to leave the Port Mafia,
ポートマフィアを抜けるのは
but it's not impossible.
容易ではないが　不可能ではない
Yet I didn't, because...
それでも私がそうしなかったのは
It's my job.
仕事ですから
You look after the girl.
娘の面倒はお前が見てやれよ
What, me?
僕がですか
Of course.
当然だ　お前が助けたんだからな
You saved her.
Okay.
Excuse me.
失礼します
We're from the city police.
市警から参りました
Oh, welcome.
ご苦労様です
Oh?
あれ　この前部下が逮捕された箕浦君じゃない
Oh Minoura-kun, your subordinate
was arrested a little while ago, right?
We're here today on a
different matter, detective.
今日は別件だ　名探偵
We have a case.
依頼があってな
Episode 11 Part 2
An Ecstatic
Detective Agency
They left as soon as they
were done talking business,
仕事の話が終わったらお茶も飲まずに帰っちゃうなんて
without even sitting down for tea.
I guess policemen in cities are busy.
都会のお巡りさんって忙しいんですね
Where you're from, do the
police have lots of free time?
お前の故郷では警察は暇なのか
Everyone knows each other in my village.
うちの村はみんな顔見知りですから
駐在さんの仕事といえば　井戸の喞筒修理に煙突の中の猫救助
A policeman's job would
be fixing the well's pump,
rescuing cats from chimneys,
and tasting the year's first watermelon.
後はその年一番の水瓜の味見ですね
なんだそれは
What the...
What happens if anyone commits a crime?
誰かが犯罪を犯したら？
The perpertrator'd get tied up
and thrown off a cliff.
犯人縛って崖から棄てます
Um, Kenji-san...
あの　賢治さんって
You can call me Kenji-kun.
君でいいですよ
Until two months ago, I was living
in a village called Ihatov
二月前までイーハトーヴォ村という
where we don't have
electricity or telephones.
電気も電話もない処で牛を追ってました
I was scouted by the president
and came to the city.
社長に勧誘されてこの都会へ
The city's full of new concepts.
I'm having a lot of fun.
都会は新しい概念ばかりで楽しいです
New? Like what?
新しいとは？
First, I don't really understand
the concept of money.
Isn't
bartering
good
enough?
Isn't
bartering
good
enough?
先ずはお金の概念がまだよくわかりません
I see.
そこから
Kunikida-san,
国木田さん　先ほどの市警からの依頼どうしましょう
what should we about the request
from the city police earlier?
A moving car blew up
for unknown reasons.
走行中の車が謎の爆発か
It'll be a challenge.
The police have given up on it.
市警も投げた難題です
Atsushi, want to give this one a try?
敦　やってみるか
Shadow another agent
and learn the ropes?
他の社員に附いて　早く仕事を覚えろ
You can do this.
お前ならやれる
Got it.
はい
What's going on?
なにあれ
What's that?
I heard a car was just going along
when it suddenly flew over there.
走行中の車が突然あそこまで吹っ飛んだそうですよ
Another explosion?
I'm not sure I'm up for this.
僕には無理かも
The driver died on impact
and he hasn't been identified.
運転手は即死で身元不明のようです
Why not?
身元不明？
Can't we identify people if their
fingerprints or teeth are intact?
指紋や歯形が残っていれば　身元ってわかるんじゃ
Yes.
ええ　残っていれば
If they were intact.
What?!
Then,
じゃあ　あの車の中ぐちゃぐちゃ
everything inside that car turned to mush?
All right,
却説　乱歩さんならここで事件解決ですけど
Rampo-san would be able to solve
the case right away here,
but our task right now is
to gather information.
我々の仕事は先ず情報を集めるところからです
Oh, Ken-chan.
あら　賢ちゃん
Oh hello, Miss Maeda.
前田のお姉さん
Thank you for the boar meat the other day.
この前貰った猪肉　ありがとうね　おいしかったわ
It was delicious.
It was extra sent from my home.
実家から送ってきた余りものです　お気になさらずに
It was nothing.
"Miss"?
「お姉さん」？
She'd be one of the
younger ladies at my village.
うちの村では若者の範疇です
Hey, boy.
おう　坊
The vegetable garden I told you about,
前に話した菜園　どうにも水捌けが悪くてな
it doesn't drain very well.
The soil might be too dry.
きっと畝の土質ですね　明日行きます
I'll come take a look tomorrow.
頼むわ
Thanks.
You're really popular.
大人気だね
Hey, Ken-chan.
よう　賢ちゃん
You on a job?
仕事かい
We're investigating the car explosion
that happened earlier today.
そこの通りであった爆発した車の件を調べています
Do you know anything?
何かご存じないですか
Oh, that.
あれなあ
There are... rumors.
噂は…あるなあ
I'm not really supposed to talk about it,
本来は云うたらあかんのやけど　若いもんが云うとったわ
but the young'uns were saying
that before it happened,
事件の前　工場区の裏通りの連中が肥料を仰山買い込んどったと
backstreet folks from the factory
district bought a load of fertilizer.
Fertilizer...
肥料？
I wonder if they realized
the beauty of farming.
畑圃場の素晴らしさに目覚めたのでしょうか
No, they were apparently talking
about manufacturing something.
いや　精製がどうとか云うとったから
Then it was probably nitrogen fertilizer.
ならきっと窒素肥料ですね
Nitrogen fertilizer?
窒素肥料？
It's an ingredient for building bombs.
爆弾の材料ですよ
What?!
Thank you as always.
いつも有り難う御座います　助かりました
It was very helpful.
賢ちゃんの為なら何でもするけぇな　仲良うしてや
I'd do anything for you, Ken-chan.
We already have a lead.
こんなに早く手掛りが　賢治君って凄い
Let's stay in touch.
Kenji-kun's amazing.
The same goes for me.
こちらこそこれからもよろしくお願いします
I'll be counting on you.
Speaking of the back streets
of the factory district,
工場区の裏通りといえば　互助青年会の皆さんの寄合所がありますね
there's a meeting hall for the
Gojo Youth Association there.
青年会？
Youth Association?
Put in city terms... a gang?
都会風に云うと　「ギャング」ですか
A g—gang?!
ギャ…ギャング？
I wonder if they're the ones
who built the bomb.
彼らが爆弾を造った犯人なのでしょうか
Well, let's go ask them face to face.
まあ　本人達に直接聞きに行きましょう
Wait a minute!
ちょっと待った
Even if they were responsible,
犯人だとしても流石に認めないだろうし　危険なんじゃ
I doubt they'd admit to it.
Won't it be risky?
If we are sincere in our
inquiries, they'll respond.
心を込めて聞けば答えてくれますよ　そういうものです
It's how things are.
I-It's how things are?
そ…そういうものって
Is it?
そういうもの？
It's...
そういう…
I guess that is how things are!
そういうものなんだ
Hey, Tanizaki.
おい　谷崎
Aren't you with Atsushi?
お前　敦と一緒じゃ
Oh, Kenji-kun went with him.
Was Off
Purchasing
Eggs on a
Limited-
Time
Only Sale
Was Off
Purchasing
Eggs on a
Limited-
Time
Only Sale
それなら賢治君が行きましたよ
What, with Kenji?!
なに　賢治と？
Yes, they went to the crime scene together.
ええ　二人で現場に
Kenji-kun's very competent.
賢治君は成績優秀で難事件を何度も解決してますし　問題ないでしょう
He's solved many difficult cases,
so I doubt there'll be problems—
大問題だ
It's a huge problem!
Kenji's methods are too unique.
He's not a good role model!
賢治のやり方は特有すぎて参考にならん
Given how simplistic
and naïve Atsushi is,
だが単純で頭が常春の敦は賢治の仕事の手順を素直に信じるに決まっている
he may easily take Kenji's
methods at face value
and believe them to be the gold standard!
Best and
Worst Team
This isn't good.
まずいぞ
Huh?!
Did you all build the bomb that
made the car go flying?
皆さんが爆弾を造って車をジャンプさせたんですか
You're funny!
くそ面白え　貴様ら警察か
You guys cops?
Not at all. We're with the
Armed Detective Agency.
いえいえ　僕達は武装探偵社です
Oh, nice chain!
いい鎖ですね
You must be keeping one on you
牛を牽引する時の為に持ち歩いてるんですね
to use when you need to herd cows.
触んな
Don't touch me!
何が狙いだ
What's your angle?!
いやー　皆さんが犯人かどうか教えてもらいたいんですよ
Oh, I just wanted you all to tell me
if you're responsible for what happened.
Huh?
Don't know anything about it.
そんな話は知らねえなあ
Right?
なあ
I see!
そうですか　それは失礼しました
I'm sorry to have bothered you.
Huh?!
Thank you for your help.
ご協力有り難う御座います
What?
H-Hey, Kenji-kun?
ちょ…ちょっと　賢治君
They were lying, no matter
how you try to look at it.
どう考えても嘘でしょ
They're the ones responsible!
あいつらが犯人だよ
They might've used the bomb to kill someone
in an opposing gang, or something.
例えば敵組織の人間を始末する為に爆弾を使ったとか
でも知らないって云ってましたよ
But they said they didn't know anything.
Well, sure, but...
確かに云ってたけど
Be it with a cow or a person,
牛でも人でも　村でも都会でも
be it in a village or a city,
素直に気持ちを話せば通じ合えるものです
if you are sincere, you can
communicate with others.
I've never failed using this method.
僕はこのやり方で失敗したことがありません
R-Really?
ほ…本当に？
Really.
はい
I guess I can see that.
それもそうだね
Shall we head back for now?
一度戻りましょうか
そうだね
Yeah.
Let's go by a beef bowl
place on our way back.
帰りに牛丼屋さんに寄りましょう　お腹減っちゃいました
I'm starving.
Kenji-kun, you can eat beef
even though you keep cows?
賢治君　牛飼ってるのに食べられるの？
I love cows!
牛は大好きですよ　飼うのも触れ合うのも食べるのも
I love having cows, communing
with cows, and eating cows.
The bomb was used to kill
an enemy gang member.
敵対組員を殺す為だった爆弾の件　まさか探偵如きに嗅ぎつけられるとはなあ
Who knew private
investigators would sniff us out?
Since you left without
really questioning us,
大した尋問もなく帰ったってことは　何か決定的な証拠を見つけたか
does that mean you found conclusive proof?
You're gonna tell the cops, aren't you?
サツに密告する気だなあ？
We won't let you.
そうはさせねえ
I see.
そうでしたか
I'm glad you went through the
trouble to tell us the truth.
本当のことを正直に話す為にご足労いただくなんて嬉しいです
Huh?
I knew sincere conversation
would lead to understanding.
矢っ張り正直に話すとわかり合えますね
In all of my cases, everyone
confesses to me like this.
僕の担当した事件では　皆さんこうやって素直に告白していただけるんですよ
Oh, I see—
なんだ　そうなんだ
One down.
先ず一人
Crap!
まずい
We're surrounded.
敵に囲まれてる　僕は今まで何をしてたんだ
What have I been doing?
Get 'em!
やっちまえ
Ow...
あいたたた
Huh?
Phew.
Oops.
よっこらせっと
Ouch...
あいたた
Oh, don't mind me.
お気になさらずに　こんなこともあります
This happens sometimes.
Out in the countryside,
cows often get in a temper
田舎では牛の機嫌が悪くて云うことを聞かないなんてしょっちゅうでした
and refuse to listen to you.
In times like that...
そういう時は
Be not defeated by the rain.
雨ニモマケズ
Be not defeated by the wind.
風ニモマケズ
Nor by the iron pipe.
鉄管ニモ
Nor by the knife.
短刀ニモ
金属打棒ニモマケヌ
Nor by the metal bat.
Be of sound body.
丈夫ナカラダヲモチ
Be without desire.
慾ハナく
Never be angered.
決シテ瞋ラズ
Always have a quiet smile.
イツモシヅカニワラッテヰル
That is whom I wish to be.
Miyazawa
Family
Motto
Miyazawa
Family
Motto
サウイフモノニ
ワタシハナリタイ
Should
Cows
Act Up,
Hit Them
With
Whatever's
Close
At Hand
Should
Cows
Act Up,
Hit Them
With
Whatever's
Close
At Hand
This won't work.
これは無理だ
I can't do things like this, Kunikida-san!
国木田さん僕には無理ですあんなやりか…
Calm down, idiot!
落ち着け　怒阿呆
I commend you for
realizing that on your own.
自分で気づいたことは褒めてやる
Kenji is gifted with superhuman strength,
賢治は怪力の異能力者だ　とはいえ万能ではない
but he isn't invincible.
He can only manifest that
strength when he's hungry.
空腹の時しかあの怪力は発現せん
Huh?
Beef Bowl
Then what happens when he's full?
じゃあ満腹になったら
I can't eat any more.
もう食べられません
He goes to sleep.
寝る
boku ga boku de irareru
I was searching for the reason
僕が僕でいられる　理由を探していた
riyuu o sagashiteita
why I'm able to stay as I am.
あなたの胸の中で　生きている僕がいるのならば
anata no mune no naka de
If there's a version of me
ikiteiru boku ga iru no naraba
that exists in your heart,
kurayami mo nagai sakamichi mo
Then even if darkness looms on this rocky road,
暗闇も長い坂道も　越えて行けるような僕になれるはず
koeteikeru you na boku ni nareru hazu
I'll be able to find the way to the new me.
それぞれに今を歩いてる僕らが笑えるように
sorezore ni ima o aruiteru bokura ga waraeru you ni
So that we can keep smiling in our own moments,
ikiteiru imi o tashikameainagara susumeru you ni
So that we can explore the meaning of life together,
生きている意味を確かめ合いながら進めるように
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
あなたがあなたでいれるように
anata ga anata de ireru you ni
So that you can stay how you are.
kanashimi ni kurete anata no namida ga koboreru toki
Whenever you're overcome by grief, and tears flow,
悲しみに暮れてあなたの涙がこぼれる時
寂しさに溢れて心がしぼんでく時
samishisa ni afureta kokoro ga shibondeku toki
Whenever your heart floods with loneliness and you waste away,
名前を呼ぶよ　あなたの名前を
namae o yobu yo anata no namae o
I'll call out a name, your name.
僕の名前を呼んでくれたみたいに
boku no namae o yondekureta mitai ni
Just as you once called out mine.
Meanwhile,
Dazai...
I'll say I got away from
the Port Mafia tomorrow.
明日ポートマフィアから脱出したことにしよっと
Episode 12
Borne Back Ceaselessly into the Past